Guide to the Southern Lesbian-Feminist Activist Herstory Project Oral Histories RL.10066
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Southern Lesbian-Feminist Activist Herstory Project
2011-2015
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Norman, Rose
Mushroom, Merril, 1942-
York, Beth
Esrig, Barbara
Ester, Barbara
RL.10066
10 Gigabytes MP3, WAV, WMA, PDF, and DOC files.
0.3 Linear Feet 1 box
Forty-four digital audio oral history interviews documenting lesbian feminist activism in the South focused on the period 1968-1994.
Scope and Contents
Forty-four digital audio oral history interviews created by Charlene Ball, Kate Ellison, Barbara Esrig, Barbara Ester, Merril Mushroom, and Rose Norman, documenting lesbian feminist activism in the South focused on the period 1968-1994. The interviews were created in 2011-2015, and are accompanied by digital notes and/or transcripts, which often contain photographs.
Biographical / Historical
The Southern Lesbian-Feminist Activist Herstory Project came into existence in 2009 around efforts at WomonWrites, an annual conference of lesbian writers, to document the lives and experiences of lesbian activists in the American South in the last decades of the 20th century. Many of the interviews were excerpted for use in special issues of Sinister Wisdom.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Southern Lesbian-Feminist Activist Herstory Project interviews were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book and Manuscript Library as a gift in 2013-2015.
Related Materials
Womonwrites Records, 1979-2014; Atlanta Lesbian Feminist Alliance Archives, ca. 1972-1994
Lesbian activists; Lesbians -- United States; Lesbians -- Southern States; Oral histories (document genre); Audiovisual materials; Southern States -- History
- Southern Lesbian-Feminist Activist Oral Histories, 2011-2015; 1
  Scope and Contents
  Interviews include digital audio and accompanying textual notes.
  - Atlanta Lesbian Feminist Alliance (ALFA) - Chris Carroll, Eleanor Smith, Lorraine Fontana - interviewed by Charlene Ball, 2013-04-02; 0:59:47 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Atlanta Lesbian Feminist Alliance (ALFA) - Saralyn Chesnut - interviewed by Charlene Ball, 2013-04-08, 2013-05-01; 0:20:40 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Atkins, Gail and Demeter, Gwen - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2013-10-12; 1:04:47 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Avery, Byllye - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2013-02-15; 0:53:14 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Beef and McEntire, Lauren - interviewed by Merril Mushroom, 2014-08-26; 0:29:55 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Boudreaux, Shewolf (Jean) - interviewed by Barbara Esrig and Kate Ellison, 2013-01 and 2013-02; 1:30:41 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Burnell, Donna - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2012-12-21; 0:52:17 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Carter, Mandy - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2013-03-26; 1:15:51 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Culver, Corky - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2012-11-10; 0:59:12 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Earl, Matilda - interviewed by Merril Mushroom, 2014-09-14; 0:38:56 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Eickmann, Krista - interviewed by Merril Mushroom, 2014-09-01; 0:28:39 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Ellison, Kate - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2012-11-10; 2:45:12 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Esrig, Barbara - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2012-11-11; 1:23:01 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Felicity, Calla and Felicity, LauRose - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2011-05-26; 0:00:20 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
    Introductory audio only, see notes for interview information and transcribed content.
  - Fougere, Myriam - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2014-01-29; 2:13:12 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Fullbright, Swamprat (Erica) - interviewed by Merrill Mushroom, 2014-09-10; 0:25:16 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Garner, Joan - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2013-04-12; 0:47:08 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Harrison, Garnett - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2012-11-16; 0:35:57 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Harrison, Sallie - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2012-11-12; 1:14:11 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Hart, Nett - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2015-01-28; 1:08:35 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Hawk, Cybilla - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2014-08-23; 1:15:30 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Hicks, Lynn - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2014-02-25; 0:34:59 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Jackson, Blanche - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2014-07-20; 1:43:01 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Lieu, Barbara - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2014-08-29; 0:37:17 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - McFadden, Naj - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2014-10-22; 0:54:18 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - McMichael, Pam - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2013-04-23; 0:58:22 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Moroles, Maria Christina - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2014-10-27; 1:42:32 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Netherton, Bonnie - interviewed by Rose Norman and Corky Culver, 2013-11-04 to 2013-11-06; 3:28:50 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Pagoda Women at Alapine - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2013-04-13; 2:25:46 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Parrish, Margaret - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2012-11-12; 0:41:42 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Pharr, Suzanne - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2013-03-28; 1:03:40 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Powell, Carole - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2012-12-31; 1:25:15 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Randall-David, Betsy - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2013-02-25; 0:56:38 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Reeder, Gail - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2011-08-15; 0:52:48 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Rivers, Diana - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2012-05-24; 0:43:47 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Saltzman, Emily - interviewed by Merril Mushroom, 2014-09-09; 0:24:12 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Segrest, Mab - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2013-05-10; 0:27:32 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Silvermoon, Flash - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2012-11-12; 0:59:53 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Sims, Mary Lee - interviewed by Barbara Ester, 2013-04-08; 1:13:25 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Smith, Pam - interviewed by Barbara Esrig, 2012-12-14; 1:38:43 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Spitzer, Mindy - interviewed by Barbara Ester, 2012-12-12; 1:08:20 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Tarpley, Connie - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2013-11-07; 0:46:52 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Williams, Rainbow - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2013-11-09; 1:27:04 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
  - Willowbee, Sally - interviewed by Rose Norman, 2015-01-23; 0:52:58 (Digital-materials RL10066-SET-0001)
- Administrative materials (Box 1)
  Includes project flash drives, and compact discs and paper copies for the Sims and Spitzer interviews.